《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
突袭机要发送信号激活病毒了
The Raiders are going to send a signal to activate the virus.
听我的口令  初始化删除程序
On my mark, initiate the computer wipe.
我正在连接网络
I'm connecting to the network now.
祝贺你 指挥官
Congratulations, Commander.
我要离开卡拉狄加 不是你
I'm leaving Galactica, not you.
我回来了
I'm coming back.
我说了
I said it.
我是认真的
I meant it.
我能理解失去你所…
I understand what it's like
在意的人时的感受
to lose someone that you care about deeply.
我们还没失去他们
They're not lost. Not yet.
我们必须返回卡布里卡
We have to go back to Caprica.
根据目前情况  我已无可选择
Given the current situation, I'm afraid that I have no alternative
我只能宣布  从现在开始  我参加总统竞选
but to announce that I am, as of now, a candidate for the Presidency.
我会输
I'm gonna lose.
进
Yes, come in.
还有1分钟 总统女士
One minute, Madam President.
谢谢你  托瑞
Thank you, Tory.
不要对我们面对的任务抱有幻想
No one should be under any illusions about what we're gonna face here.
我们的最后一次跳跃将到达距地面...
Our final jump will take us intra-atmosphere,
不到两公里的大气层内
less than two clicks above the surface.
我们也可能会遭到猛烈袭击
We're also expecting to take heavy fire.
模拟演习表明  我们可能会损失近20%的兵力
Simulations indicate losses of up to 20% can be expected.
百分之二十!
20%!
所以此次任务
That's why this mission has been designated
被指挥部定为2A级
as Two-Alpha by the command authority.
自愿报名
It's volunteer only.
谁想退出
You want out,
就趁现在
now's the time.
我知道你现在不太相信这种事 但如果你有信心
I know it's hard to believe right now, but if you have faith,
一切都会按天意行事
everything will turn out exactly as it should.
我不喜欢输
I don't like to lose.
要有信心
Have faith.
我就要面对公众的羞辱了
I'm about to face public humiliation,
你却还在老调重弹
and you are singing the same old song.
我可有些烦了
I'm a little tired of the melody.
哦
Oh.
不好意思弄得这么乱 这算是一种仪式
Sorry about the mess. It's a bit of a ritual.
有点迷信色彩
Superstition, really.
我以前在委员会的 听证会上作证前就这样
I used to do this before testifying at committee hearings.
我会这样 先拿出一张卡片
This is what I do. I take...
记住论点 然后把卡片撕掉
Memorize the talking points, then tear the card,
让碎片自由落地  这样挺奏效的
let the pieces fall as they may. It helps.
我父亲在开庭前  通常是折断铅笔
Yeah, my father used to break pencils before he went into court,
然后再向文员借
then borrow one from the clerk.
代表丢掉成见  以事实为依据
Break preconceptions. Work with what you have.
我喜欢
You know, I like that.
我看看
Let me see.
我喜欢
I like it.
不错
That's good.
感觉好些了?
Feel better?
恩 那如果主持人没有铅笔怎么办?
Yeah, but what happens if the moderator doesn't have a pencil?
那你惨了
Then you're pretty screwed.
哦
Oh.
不是吧
Oh, no.
我上高中的时候在每次辩论前...
I used to get the giggles before debate team
就总是傻笑
in high school.
进
Yes?
到时间了  总统女士
It's time, Madam President.
谢谢  托瑞
Thank you, Tory.
很多人还不知道被捕获的重型赛昂突袭机的跳跃距离
What many of you don't know is that the captured Cylon Heavy Raider
要比我们的猛禽远很多
is capable of much longer jumps than our Raptors.
事实上  我们较早前才发现...
In fact, we realized early on
我们可以把重型突袭机的导航系统
that if we could install the Heavy Raider navigational system
安装到我们的一艘猛禽号上
aboard one of our Raptors,
攻击小队在10次跳跃之内...
a strike team could make the entire trip back to Caprica
就可以返回卡布里卡
in less than 10 jumps.
到目前为止 一个限制我们的因素就是...
Now, the limiting factor up until now
无法将赛昂计算机安装到我们的计算机上
has been our inability to install the Cylon computer with our computer.
而现在这个障碍已被克服了
That obstacle has now been overcome.
她是来帮助我们的
She's here to help us.
她会布置我们的航标
She's gonna lay out our navigational markers
更新我们的跳跃坐标
and update our jump coordinates.
谁有异议吗?
Does anyone have a problem with that?
你是被全能的神选中来引领这些人的
You've been chosen to lead these people by Almighty God.
这是必然的结果
It will happen.
那婴儿的遭遇也是必然吗?
Like the baby happened?
那个我命中注定要保护的婴儿
The one I was destined to protect?
不要只因愤怒就亵渎神明  盖尤斯
Don't let your anger drive you into blasphemy, Gaius.
还有两周才开始竞选
The election's still two weeks away.
打起精神
Get your act together.
准备好了么?
You ready?
恩  我只是小睡了片刻
Yeah, I was just taking a little nap.
上士
Chief?
这是我们的任务
This is our mission.
营救那些被我们丢下的人是我们的职责
It's our duty to the people we left behind.
如果要我们用赛昂人来救他们  那也无可厚非
And if we need to use a Cylon to get them back, then so be it.
我们要尽可能营救卡布里卡上的幸存者
This is about trying to get as many survivors off Caprica as we can.
然而 这仍是一项2A级任务
Even so, it's still Two-Alpha.
有人要退出么?
Anyone want to eject?
全体起立
Commander on deck!
别担心  我就呆一会 我也想听听
Don't worry. I won't be long. I want to hear it, too.
你可以尽量想些严肃的事
You just have to really try to think about something serious.
这样会有用
That always helps. All right?
举个例子?
Like what?
像是...
Well, like...
这可好
Great.
从这个距离展开营救是史无前例的
No one has ever attempted a rescue mission from this distance,
更别说是深入敌后
much less behind enemy lines.
即使只是尝试  你们也是创造历史的人
You'll be making history just by making the attempt.
但如果能把这些人从卡布里卡带回来
But bring these people back from Caprica,
你们将是创造未来的一份子
and you'll be making part of the future.
有问题么?
Questions?
如果你们能在我们回来之前找到地球 能帮我们占几个座位么?
If you guys find Earth before we get back, will you save us a few seats?
地球?  如果我们能找到个有吃有喝的星球
Earth, hell, we find any rock with food and water,
我会给你们开个酒吧
I'll build you guys a bar.
好了
All right.
看到了吧? 我说过我就呆一会
See? I told you I wouldn't be long.
盖塔先生 打开无线电
Mr. Gaeta, turn on the wireless.
让他们看看在今后的5天内
Let's give these people a chance to hear
他们会错过什么好戏
what kind of fun they'll be missing for the next five days.
再过几分钟
McMANUS:We're just minutes away
总统大选第一场辩论即将开始
from the start of the first presidential
辩论将在总统劳拉·罗丝琳
debate between President Laura Roslin...
你还好吗
You okay?
及其对手副总统盖尤斯·波塔尔之间展开
...and her opponent, Vice President Gaius Baltar.
我能走了吗?
Can I go now?
所有问题…
All the questions...
曼德森下士
Corporal Madsen.
均由民用舰队的成员提交
...submitted by members of the civilian fleet here
其所涵盖的题目极为广泛
cover a wide range of topics.
所以请关注总统大选…
So, please, stay tuned as we get set now
第一场辩论
for the first of two presidential debates.
等待两位候选人及其助手到来的这段时间里
The atmosphere in the auditorium is tense as we await the arrival
礼堂内弥漫着紧张的气氛
of the two candidates and their aides.
对于副总统波塔尔来说  今晚的压力将着实不小
The real pressure will be on Vice President Baltar tonight...
上士
Chief?
副总统盖尤斯·波塔尔...
Bullseye. Here comes Vice President Gaius Baltar
走进了会场 此时我们正在等待总统女士的到来
into the room as we await Madam President.
劳拉·罗丝琳在此刻所得到的票数遥遥领先
Laura Roslin is very much ahead in the polls at this point.
我相信很快...
I believe that
她就会入场  我们仍在等待她的到来
she's entering the room shortly, but still, of course, waiting for her.
副总统波塔尔在一个月前
He is capable of blindsiding her
宣布竞选总统使她大为吃惊
as he did when he launched his candidacy a month ago.
当然  波塔尔博士是我们这一代人
Dr. Baltar, of course, has long been admired
最为钦佩的赋有才干的科学家
as one of the most brilliant scientific minds of his generation
并在挽救人类免遭赛昂人威胁中  扮演着重要的角色
and played a critical role in saving the human race from the Cylon threat.
总统来了
Yes, here comes the President now.
劳拉·罗丝琳总统走进了会场
Laura Roslin, the President, has entered the room.
我会让你输得一败涂地  盖尤斯
I'm going to wipe the floor with you, Gaius.
…握手 交换意见
...shake hands, exchange a few words.
你肯定是又疯了
You must be losing your mind again.
你就只能想出这句话来对答?
If that's the best you can come up with,
你可有大麻烦了 祝你好运
you really are in trouble. Good luck.
怎么样? 没事吧?
How you doing? You okay?
莎伦?
Sharon.
别不理我 至少现在别这样
Don't shut me out, not now.
要发生某种不详的事了  西洛
Something dark is coming, Helo.
我有预感
I can feel it.
我能感到它正蠢蠢欲动 等待着
I can feel it lurking out there, waiting.
什么意思?  等回到卡布里卡以后吗?
What do you mean? Back on Caprica?
不
No.
不是在执行任务的时候 并不是什么具体的事
Not on a mission, not any specific thing.
更像是一段黑暗的时期
It's more like a dark time.
上士
Chief?
来人啊!
Help!
蒂罗尔上士
Chief Tyrol,
我是卡维尔修士 听说你主动要求宗教咨询
I'm Brother Cavil. I understand you've asked for religious counseling.
我从来不相信心理治疗  家父曾是一名牧师
I never really believed in psychotherapy. My father was a priest.
我懂了
I see.
你认为牧师要比医生更容易相处些  好
You thought you'd have an easier time with a priest than a real doctor. Okay.
我每晚...
I pray to the gods
都会向神祷告
every night,
但我想他们并没有听到我的祷告
but I don't think they listen to me.
祷告只能白费力气  这你知道吗?
Do you know how useless prayer is?
诵扬  歌唱…
Chanting and singing
那些陈词滥调
and mucking about with old half-remembered lines of bad poetry,
你知道你会得到什么吗?
and you know what it gets you?
一无所获
Exactly nothing.
你真是一个牧师么?
Are you sure you're a priest?
你没出世之前  我就已经开始传教了
I've been preaching longer than you've been sucking down oxygen.
在那段时间里  我知道了...
And in that time, I've learned enough to know
神是不会显灵的
that the gods don't answer prayers.
我们要靠自己  这是老天定下的规矩
We're here on our own. That's the way they set things up.
我们只能自己去寻找答案 独自走出荒原
We have to find our own answers, our own way out of the wilderness
我们的面前并没有那条提前铺好的光明大道
without a nice little sunny path all laid out in front of us in advance.
我就是在这么做
That's what I'm trying to do.
在努力寻找自己的路
I'm trying to find my way.
在你没有发现症结所在之前
Now, it's not gonna get better
你不会有什么转变的
until you see what the problem is.
而症结就是你自己六神无主 心神不宁
And the problem is you are screwed up, heart and mind.
是你自己 不关老天  命运或是宇宙的事
You, not the gods or fate or the universe.
是你自己的事
You.
多谢鼓励
Thanks for the pep talk.
嗨
Hey.
你好
Hi.
我只想说...
I just wanted to say,
嗯
well,
祝你好运
good hunting.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
计划不错
Yeah, it's a good plan.
挺好的
It's a good plan.
莎伦应该能协助你们跳跃到
Sharon should be able to jump you into the atmosphere
距地面几公里的大气层内
a couple of clicks above the surface.
避开赛昂人的德丝侦察 这我知道
Down below the Cylon dradis. I know the plan.
李 是我制定的计划
Lee, I wrote it.
对
Yeah.
我得走了
I gotta go.
我希望你能找到他  卡拉
I hope you find him, Kara.
真的
I really do.
我也希望如此
So do I.
殖民快电称
From the Colonial dispatch,
昨晚的辩论只能说明…
"Last night's debate only solidified the perception... "
总统女士  等会再说
MAN: Madam President. I'll do that later.
"波塔尔博士  尽管魅力不凡
"... that Dr. Baltar, for all his charm, is essentially an empty suit
但遭遇实质性的政策问题的时候 也只能说是虚有其表"
"when it comes to matters of substantive policy. "
媒体可算是说对了一回
It's nice to see the press is getting it right for a change.
别忘了激进的宗教指控是危险的
Don't forget, the radical religious charge is dangerous.
对于一个绝望的人来说  也许这是卑鄙手段
It may be a low blow from a desperate man,
但这是他挽回颓势的唯一话题
but it's the only issue he's managed to get any traction on.
他会继续在这个问题上大作文章
He will keep exploiting it.
他需要找个比这更有影响力的话题
He's gotta come up with something much, much bigger than that
只想借此作为选举的中心话题
if he wants to make it the central issue of his campaign.
那可行不通
It's not gonna work.
你要继续用宗教的话题来攻击她
You gotta keep hitting her on the religious thing.
每当你提到这方面的事
Every time we go there,
我们的票数就会增加
you score points, and we move the polls in our direction.
我不知道你是否意识到了  汤姆
Yes, I'm not sure if you're aware, Tom,
但民众可不会选举…
but the mob isn't usually in the habit of electing ungodly apostates
侮辱他们神灵的背教者
who denigrate people of faith.
事情会有转机的 你看着吧
Things are gonna turn around. You'll see.
他说得对
He's right.
听他的
Listen to him.
当然
Of course.
我真是鼠目寸光 谢谢你
Of course. How blind I'm being. Thank you, yes.
"事情会有转机的"
"Things are gonna turn around. You'll see. "
这算是什么?建议吗?
What is that? Advice?
谢谢你独到的眼光
Well, thank you. Thank you for your keen insight,
你那惊人的政治头脑
your astounding political acumen.
我现在确信
You know, I'm so assured right now, Tom,
自己只需按兵不动
I'm just gonna sit right back and wait for the hand of God
听天由命就可以了
to reach down and change my political fortunes.
你说怎么样?
How about that?
卡拉狄加  我是星芭儿
Galactica, Starbuck.
搜救队确认准备完毕 我们已开启超光速引擎
SAR squadron confirms readiness check, and we are spun up out here
准备进行第一次跳跃
and ready for the first jump.
你们可以跳跃了 星芭儿
DUALLA: You are go for the jump, Starbuck.
收到
Roger that.
10分钟后跳跃 计时开始
Jump in ten minutes. Mark.
卡拉狄加  我想与指挥官通话
Galactica, I'd like to speak with Actual.
长官
Sir?
我是指挥官  说吧
Actual. Go.
我对你说过谢谢吗?
Did I ever say thank you?
没有 如果是那样 太阳就从西边出来了
No, but then again, that would be a first, wouldn't it?
谢谢你
Thank you.
你能安然无恙回来就算谢我了
Just come back in one piece. That'll be thank you enough.
祝你好运 指挥官通话完毕
Good hunting. Actual out.
搜救队  我是星芭儿 输入导航数据重新核对坐标
SAR Team, Starbuck. Set navcom inputs to coordinate re-check.
准备执行反馈程序 与稳定化程序
Standby for bounce-back and stabilization routines.
进行最后一次核对  各位
Let's do a final check, people.
疯子 检查完毕
Headcase. Check.
剑客 检查完毕
Swordsman. Check.
铁砧 检查完毕    还是想不到你居然说服了我
Anvil. Check. I still can't believe you talked me into this.
头巾 检查完毕
Chinstrap. Check.
这事很重要
It's important.
警灯 检查完毕
Gumball. Check.
来去都会由我来陪着你
And I'll be with you there and back.
不管发生什么事 从现在开始只有我和你
It's you and me from now on, no matter what.
这是我们说好了的
Just like we agreed.
我知道  真的很感谢你  真的
I know. I know. I really appreciate it, Helo. I really do.
生肉 检查完毕
Raw Meat. Check.
托伊 检查完毕
Toyon. Check.
斯塔库斯 检查完毕
Strakus. Check.
我就是忘不了她
I just can't get her out of my head,
我们的小姑娘
our little girl.
花花公子 检查完毕
Playboy. Check.
波洛 检查完毕
Polo. Check.
凯西 检查完毕
Casey. Check.
阿多尼斯 检查完毕
Adonis. Check.
有问题吗?
Is there a problem?
古力曼 检查完毕
Gully Man. Check.
星云 检查完毕
Star Cloud. Check.
雷丝克 检查完毕
Racetrack. Check.
加兰 检查完毕
Callan. Check.
无线电检查完毕
Wireless check complete.
准备完毕  可以开始了
Board is green, and we are set.
莎伦 到你了
Sharon, you're on.
准备好了
Ready.
搜救队  我是星芭儿
SAR Team, Starbuck.
准备按我口令进行跳跃
Standby to jump on my mark.
五
Five.
开始了 四
Here we go. Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
开始第1次跳跃
Commence the first jump.
这看起来不对呀
This doesn't look right.
雷达上没有信号
No other contacts on dradis.
什么?
What?
老天  咱们跳到错误的坐标上了
Oh, man. We're at the wrong jump coordinates.
干
Frak!
西洛  我们这就开始少人了
Helo, we've lost someone already.
是雷丝克
It's Racetrack.
那我们要回去么?
Should we go back?
行动守则规定  除非我们失去三组人才返回
Mission rules say we keep going unless we lose three,
所以我们继续
so we keep going.
雷丝克只能独自回母舰了
Racetrack will just have to find her way back to base.
开局还真不理想
It's a hell of a way to start, though.
我们来谈一下发生了什么事
Let's... Let's talk about what happened.
我真不敢相信  凯莉...
I can't really believe that Cally...
真想不出我怎么会那样对待凯莉
I don't understand how I could do that to Cally.
真像是一场噩梦
It's like it's a nightmare.
她说她发现你的时候 你正在睡觉
She said you were asleep when she found you.
她叫你的时候你是不是在做噩梦?
Were you having a nightmare when she woke you up?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
哦
Oh.
最近是否反复在做同样的一个梦?
Been having any recurring dreams lately?
不是
No.
好 在牧师的这个行业中我们把这叫做说谎
Okay, that's what we in the pray trade call a lie.
而说谎对你没好处
And lies aren't gonna get you anywhere, my friend.
所以咱们就别来这些
So skip over the denials and the deceptions,
有话直说  好么?
and let's get right down to it, shall we?
你做了梦
You're having dreams.
什么梦?
What are they?
告诉我你做了什么梦  上士
Tell me about your dream, Chief.
每晚都是同样的一个梦
Every night... Every night it's the same.
有多久了?
For how long?
几周
Couple of weeks.
当凯莉叫你的时候
And you were having the same dream
你正做着同样的梦  是吧?
when Cally woke you up, weren't you?
不知道 不记得了 也许是吧
I don't know. I don't remember. Maybe.
也许吧 这有关系吗?
Maybe. It doesn't matter, does it?
我只记得倒在地上的凯莉和血
All I remember is Cally on the ground and the blood.
她阻止了你
She stopped you.
她把你叫醒  你才没有实现…
By waking you up, she prevented you from carrying out
自杀的内心愿望
your secret desire to kill yourself.
我没有想自杀的内心愿望
I don't have a secret desire to kill myself.
说得对 这不是秘密
Well, actually, you're right. It's not a secret.
你明显要自杀  但问题是为什么?
You obviously want to kill yourself. Question is, why?
我看导航固件有些小故障
Look, I think there was some kind of glitch in the navcom firmware.
我们至少…
Hey, bottom line, we're to hell and gone
没抵达预定位置 机长
from where we're supposed to be, Skipper.
好吧 还能赶上他们么?
Okay, any chance that we can still catch up with them?
没机会了 行动守则规定我们得返回母舰
Not a chance. Mission rules say we head back.
他娘的  这是第一次跳跃啊
Frak me! It was the first jump!
可这些坐标是你给我的
Hey, look, you gave me these coordinates.
对…
Yeah...
回母舰吧
Back to the barn.
我收到了一个巨大的星体信号
Hey, I'm picking up a large planetary body.
挺他妈近的
It's frakking close.
哪来的?
Where did that come from?
我怎么知道
Hell if I know.
雷达上有太多干扰信号了 我刚才都没发现
There's so much dradis interference here, it didn't even register.
检查一下
Let's check this out.
空气中有氮气和氧气
Atmosphere is nitrogen-oxygen.
有机分子光谱 淡水
Organic molecular spectra. Fresh water.
知道这是什么意思吗?  这是可居住的星球
Hey, you know what this is? It's habitable.
我们可能找到了一个人类可以栖息的星球
We may have just found a world that can support human life.
看来咱们也不算是猪头
Maybe we're not just a bunch of frakups after all.
气候指数都在人类可接受的标准内
Now, the climate readings overall are within human norms.
我们无法承受两极处的严寒
Oh, there's some extremes at the poles that we couldn't withstand,
但这种情况不太常见
but that's not unusual.
干得好
Well done.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir. Thank you, sir.
河口这个位置有个斑块 可能是一个三角洲
We got a mottled area here at the river mouth, so it's probably a delta,
可能会有重要的动植物
and chances are we've got significant plant and animal life,
所以在这一区域多做几次慢速的低空飞行
so I want a lot of nice low passes across here.
听说帕伽索斯的考察队发现了野生动物
I heard the Pegasus survey mission found wildlife.
果树  鱼米之乡
Fruit trees, rivers of milk and honey.
你忘说安宝莎之湖了
Yeah, you forgot the lakes of ambrosia.
大多数的星球都是不毛之地
Most of the planet is actually pretty barren.
动植物都在赤道周围的温和地带
Plant and animal life located in a temperate belt around the equator.
但关键在于 由于星云对雷达的干扰
But the best part is, with all the dradis interference from the nebula,
赛昂人可能永远不会发现它
the Cylons will probably never find it.
谁去管那什么狗屁星球
BALTAR: Who cares about this stupid planet anyway?
都是空欢喜一场
All this song and dance over nothing.
只有不到20%的区域 才可以供人栖息  所以...
Less than 20% of that place actually supports human life, so...
你并没有放眼全局呀
You're not seeing the big picture.
这是你们的新家
This is your new home,
是你们开始新生活的地方
the place where you will lead a new life.
这就是未来  盖尤斯
This is the future, Gaius.
这个想法真郁闷
Now, there's a depressing thought.
什么?
What's that?
没什么  汤姆
Oh, nothing, Tom.
只是...
Just...
你能想象我们真要在那上面居住吗?
Can you imagine if we actually had to live on that thing?
你是一个天才
You are a genius.
又能怎样?
And?
用点心 你要赢得大选了
Pay attention. You're about to win the election.
不好意思 你刚才说什么  汤姆?
I'm sorry. What were you saying, Tom?
我们需要一个能让我们和罗丝琳划清界线的话题
We needed an issue, something to set us apart from Roslin,
一个让她与群众产生对立的重要话题
something to put her clearly on the wrong side of a major issue
这个话题必须是群众所热衷的
our people care passionately about.
就是它了
This is it.
在这星球上的永久定居
Permanent settlement on this planet.
永久定居在这里?
Permanent settlement, here?
你疯了吗?
Have you lost your marbles?
它看上去可能毫无生气
It may look dreary. It may be dreary.
但这确实是脚踩大地
But it's solid ground under your feet
头顶蓝天
and real sky over your head.
你可想不到对于那些被关在铜墙铁壁中9个月的人
You'd be surprised what a powerful idea that is to people
这有何等的诱惑力
cooped up in metal boxes for nine months.
你应该听他的  盖尤斯
You should listen to him, Gaius.
他和你一样是个聪明帅气的人
He's a smart, sexy man, just like you.
得了吧
Oh, give up.
什么?
What?
放弃寻找地球
Give up on Earth.
对
Yes.
我们在这里定居?
So we'd settle here.
对
Yes.
这小星球…
You know, it's starting to look
越看越顺眼了
like a lovely little planet after all.
这是一个中途站 一个补给食物和水的地方
This is a rest stop, a place to load up on food and water.
我们显然不会定居在这里
We're not settling here, obviously.
您也听到船长们的报告了
You've heard the captains' reports.
舰队中各船上都有人 乞求  恳求
Every ship in the fleet has people begging, pleading,
要求到上面呆一会
demanding they get time down on the surface,
即使是几小时也行
even if it's only for a few hours.
呆几小时…
Well, a few hours is one thing,
和永久定居是两码事
but permanent settlement's quite another.
突然间 波塔尔为那些希望呼吸真正空气
Suddenly, Baltar is holding out hope of breathing real air,
种植真正食物 在床上睡而不是卧铺上睡
growing real food, sleeping in a bed instead of a bunk,
在屋里住而不是船上住的人 带来了希望
living in a house instead of a ship.
这是幻想 看看任务报告
It's a fantasy. Look at the mission reports.
所有的数据表明 在这星球上居住会举步为艰
All the data indicate that life on this planet would be hard.
住几年都很难
It would be a struggle to even eke a living out for a few years.
就今天的票数看来
Today's polls show that he's also making headway with the idea
他在以这星球是在一个星云里
that because the planet is hidden in a nebula,
从而可以躲避赛昂人这个想法来拉拢选票
it will provide a refuge from the Cylons.
怎么  我们是不是认为 赛昂人的科技不够先进
What, are we now assuming that Cylon technology
找不到这个星球吗?  我们可找到了
is not sufficient enough to find this planet? We just found it.
总统女士  依我看来
Madam President, in my opinion,
民众是为他们的希望投票 而不是恐惧
people vote their hopes, not their fears.
波塔尔是在迎合民众
Baltar is offering them what they want to hear,
而您在为他们展现一个残酷的现实
and you're offering them a bitter reality.
我在告诉他们实情
I'm offering them the truth.
他们不想听实情 他们精疲力尽 心力憔悴
They don't want to hear the truth. They're tired, exhausted.
马上放下负担
The idea of stopping, laying down their burdens
开始新生活
and starting a new life right now
才是选民们众所期盼的
is what is resonating with the voters.
这样的期盼有多大的威力?
How well is it resonating?
可以让整个选举的形势产生逆转
It could turn the entire election around.
为什么你要逃避?
Why are you running?
我没有
I'm not.
你还要像这样多久?
How long are you gonna do this?
还要拒绝接受…
How long are you gonna refuse to see
摆在你面前的事实
what's right in front of your face?
算了  我不管了
How... Forget it. I'm done.
怎么? 你要走了?
What? You're leaving?
对  我不管了
That's right. I'm done.
不想和你再来回周旋了
I'm done dancing around the truth with you.
你自己清楚是怎么回事
You know what's going on,
但你却不愿意去面对 所以…
but you can't or you won't face it, so...
我不是心理辅导员
I'm not a therapist.
我不会握着你的手  对你嘘寒问暖
I'm not gonna hold your hand and help you along.
我只想尽力让你恢复正常  能正确地看待你的神
I'm just trying to get you right with yourself and with your gods,
可你却不乐意
but you're not willing to do it.
但我...
But...
我都不明白你在说什么
I don't even know what you're talking about.
看在老天的份上  上士  拜托
Oh, for gods' sake, Chief, come on!
你以为自己是赛昂人
You think you're a Cylon.
我不是赛昂人
I am not a Cylon.
你当然不是
Well, of course you're not,
可你害怕的就是这事
but that's what you're afraid of, isn't it?
害怕自己可能是赛昂人 但却像布玛儿一样浑然不觉  是吧?
That you might be a Cylon and not even know it, just like Boomer, right?
是吧?
Right?
就是这个念头使你 夜不能寐  寝食难安
That's the thought that's torturing your dreams and crippling your soul.
"我和莎伦一样是赛昂人  我该死"
"I'm a Cylon, just like Sharon, and I deserve to die. "
莎伦并不她是什么
Sharon didn't know what she was.
她只是总是想到
She just kept thinking...
感到自己会做出什么可怕的事
Feeling that she was gonna do this terrible thing,
但她自己清楚必须要阻止自己
but she knew that she had to stop herself before she did.
而你认为自己也会那样?
And you think that's what you're going to do, some terrible thing.
事实上这是可能的
Well, the truth is, you might,
可不是因为你是赛昂人
but not because you're a Cylon,
而是因为你是人类
because you're a human being
人类则一直都在做着可怕的事
and human beings do terrible things all the time.
你怎么就知道我是人类?
Well, how do you know I'm human?
可能因为我是赛昂人
Oh, well, maybe because I'm a Cylon,
而在我们开会的时候从没见过你
and I've never seen you at any of the meetings.
我也帮不了你什么了
There's not much more I can do for you.
你还是回去工作
You're gonna have to go back to work
把这些事都抛在脑后吧
and try and leave all of this behind you.
不  我...
No, I...
我做不到
I can't.
我无法去面对甲板上的人
I can't go back and face the deck people again. Are you...
还有凯莉
And Cally!
你最好回去 那是你唯一的家
Well, you better. That's the only family you've got.
要把他们当成你的家人 他们是爱你的
Just know that that's your family and that they love you.
就算是凯莉 特别是凯莉
Even Cally. Especially Cally.
如果你怀疑自己的人性和本性
If you doubt your humanity and your essential nature as a human being,
你只需在他们身上寻找
all you need to do is look to them
你一直所追寻的神的救赎
for the salvation you've been seeking from the gods.
"天助互助者"  上士
The gods lift up those who lift each other, Chief.
搜救队  我是星芭儿 我们在这里准备
SAR Team, Starbuck. We are set here.
准备到卡布里卡的最后一次跳跃
Stand by for final jump to Caprica.
记住我们会离地面很近
Remember, we are going very low to the surface.
为可能发生的 风切  下雨  风暴  任何事做好准备
Be prepared for wind shear, rain, storms, anything.
收到  星芭儿
Roger that, Starbuck.
准备好了?
Ready?
好了
Ready.
开始 跳跃
Here we go. Jump.
搜救队  我是星芭儿  和我列队
SAR Team, Starbuck. Form up on me.
收到  我是机长
Copy that, Skipper.
有赛昂人吗  西洛?
Any Cylons, Helo?
雷达上没有动静
Nothing on dradis.
等下  等下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
少了1架猛禽号 我只看到17架
We're missing a Raptor. I'm only reading 17 out there.
我们少了612号
We're missing Raptor 612.
是泰夫和凯罗索
That's Toughguy and Carousel.
怎么? 他们跳到错误的坐标上了?
What, they jumped to the wrong coordinates?
不
No, no, no.
我收到了他们的应答器 他们跳跃到这里了
I'm picking up their transponder, so they made it.
方向8-2-7  接近4-4-3  离这里大约半公里
Bearing 827 carom 443, about a half click from here.
也就是说他们在...
That would put them...
老天
Oh, my gods.
在哪里  西洛? 说话
Where, Helo? Talk to me.
他们跳到山里了
They jumped inside the mountain.
该死
Damn.
搜救队  我是星芭儿  我们损失了612号
SAR Team, Starbuck. We've lost Raptor 612.
我们继续前进
We are proceeding without them.
跟着我
Follow me.
收到  星芭儿
Roger that, Starbuck.
我认为我个人的立场
BALTAR: So I would think that my position
和我的竞选立场已经十分清楚了
and the position of my campaign is abundantly clear.
谢谢
Thank you.
总统女士 您有30秒作答时间
McMANUS: Madam President, you have 30 seconds to respond.
我首先要说的还是那句老话
Well, my initial response is, there he goes again.
女士们  先生们
Once again, ladies and gentlemen,
波塔尔博士仍在扭曲摆在我们面前的事实
Dr. Baltar is distorting the real issues before us.
真正的问题并非是
The issue here, the real question, is not
是否允许经文来左右政府的政策
allowing the scriptures to dictate the policy of this government.
而是经文中是否包含着与现实世界相关的信息?
The question is, do the scriptures contain real-world relevance?
这其中是否包含指引我们去一个更安全的家园的必要信息呢?
Do they contain the information necessary to guide us to a safer home
而不是去一个刚被我们发现的
than some completely unknown planet
完全陌生的星球呢?
that we've just now discovered?
很明显 我的答案是肯定的
Obviously, my answer to that question is yes.
我会一如既往地去探求
I have always and will continue to feel
经文中与现实世界相关的信息
the scriptures hold real-world relevance.
副总统先生  下一个是您的问题
Mr. Vice President, the next question is for you.
您所提出的在这个星球上永久定居
How do you respond to the charges
被一些人看作是投机取巧的赌博
that you've seized the idea of permanent settlement on this planet
这您作何反应呢?
as an opportunistic gamble?
有些人则解释为是因您的选票落后
Some would say it's to be construed as a desperate move
而放手一搏
from a campaign that was falling behind in every poll.
这是一个...
Well, you know, that is...
一个非常好的问题  谢谢
That is an excellent question, in fact, Jim. Thank you.
我很高兴有机会对此作出回应
And I am only too glad to have the opportunity to respond to it.
你们也知道  长久以来我一直是寻找地球的支持者
You see, I have long been a proponent in the search for Earth.
这个诺言是不仅要找到一个新的家园
The promise of perhaps finding not only a new home
并希望我们失散已久的兄弟姐妹
but also the prospect of discovering
所在的第13殖民地是繁荣富强的
our long lost brothers and sisters of the 13th Colony is a powerful one,
和我朝思暮想的一样强大
and one I have believed in heart and soul,
但问题在于 赛昂人对我们紧追不舍
but the trouble is, the Cylons continue to follow us
在殖民地沦陷后
as they have done every step of the way
便一直如此
since the destruction of the Colonies.
如果我们有机会改变这个局面 结束这样的致命追击
And if we have a chance to change this dynamic, to stop this deadly chase,
我们该抓住这个机会吗?  我的回答是肯定的
shouldn't we take it? My answer is yes.
对 继续
MAN: Oh, yeah. Come on.
谢谢 总统女士  30秒
Thank you. Madam President, 30 seconds.
我们根本无法确定赛昂人
There's no assurance, none whatsoever,
是否已经知道了这个星球
that the Cylons don't already know about this planet,
是否会为了寻找我们而定期检查这里
that they don't make regular stops here looking for us,
或是他们就等我们定居后
and that, in fact, they aren't simply waiting for us
再来攻击…
to settle on the surface so they can attack us...
我必须回答一下 必须简单地说一下
I have to respond to that. I simply have to respond to that.
给您15秒
I'll give you 15 seconds.
各位  你们所看到的是
What you've seen right now, ladies and gentlemen,
总统用恐惧 来推动她的竞选的另一个实证
is another example of the President using fear to drive her campaign.
恐惧
Fear.
对神的恐惧
Fear of the gods.
对赛昂人的恐惧 对恐惧本身的恐惧
Fear of the Cylon. Fear of fear itself.
难道不是该无所畏惧的时候了吗?
Is it not time to stop being afraid?
我恳请各位...
I'm asking all of us
不要再逃命了 开始生活吧
to stop running from our lives and start living them.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢  今天就到这里
Thank you. That is all we have time for today.
我要对今天两位候选人的坦诚表示感谢
I'd like to thank both the candidates for their frankness today.
另人激动的辩论
A very exciting debate.
还要感谢各位助理
And this concludes the cycle of the debates for the Presidency.
投票将在3天内开始   请投票
The polls will open in three days. Please vote.
谢谢  晚安
Thank you and good night.
今晚你不在状态啊
Not your night, I guess.
你去死吧
Why don't you go frak yourself?
和我在一起的是波塔尔博士的竞选总干事 汤姆·泽瑞克先生
MAN:With me now is campaign manager for Dr. Baltar, Mr. Tom Zarek.
汤姆  欢迎你  今天你也在场
Tom, welcome. You were in there with us today.
你有什么感想?
What was your impression?
波塔尔博士的讲话非常出色
ZAREK: Well, I thought Dr. Baltar did exceptionally well.
阐明了他对未来的看法
Laid out his vision of the future
并为民众指明逃离苦海的途径
and offered the people a way to end the suffering and terror
让许多人明白了生活的意义
that defines so many of their lives.
另外  我倒想知道罗丝琳
On the other hand, I found myself wondering
反对定居的理由怎么能站住脚
how Roslin's arguments against settlement could possibly win.
小心 跟着我走
Watch your footing over here. On me. Let's go.
就在那边
Get up to that line, right there.
发现了吗
Got it?
好吧 停下来
All right, hold it.
看看我们在哪儿  卡尔
Let's figure out where we are, Karl.
抵抗军的营地还有1公里远
Resistance base camp was still another click ahead.
11点方向有动静
Movement. 11:00.
友军?
Friendlies?
你们中有叫萨缪尔·安德斯的吗?
You got a Samuel T. Anders there?
你们中有叫卡拉·瑟瑞丝的吗?
BAROLAY: Is there a Kara Thrace there?
如果有的话 你告诉她 她可真是一个慢郎中
If there is, you tell her she took her good sweet time getting here.
友军
Friendlies.
怎么这么久才来?
What took you so long?
我们有陆战队和猛禽号
We got Marines and Raptors.
我们会救你们出去的
We're gonna get you and your people out of here, okay?
言而有信  是吧?
As good as your word, huh?
恩  我他妈言而有信
Yeah, good as my frakking word.
怎么?以为我会丢下你不管?
What, did you think I was gonna leave you here?
现在觉得自己是大白痴了吧?
Now you feel like a big frakking idiot, don't you?
你就闭嘴 只管救我们出去吧
All right, just shut up and save us already, okay?
各位  这是好事 可鬼子们还在我们后面
Okay, people, this is nice, but we have toasters on our ass.
其他人呢?
Where are the rest of your people?
就这么多了
This is it.
鬼子们今早偷袭了我们的营地
Toasters hit our base camp this morning.
我们人数死伤过半
I lost half my crew.
炮火来袭!
Incoming!
后撤
MARINE: Pull back!
回猛禽号!
Back to the Raptors!
不!
No!
弹道轨迹在我们和猛禽号之间
The shell trajectories are between us and the Raptors!
我们的退路被封死了
We're cut off!
有人牺牲了
MARINE: Men down!
呆在原地! 呆在原地!
Stay right there! Stay right there!